Guide to the Social Ethics Pamphlet Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Corporate Bodies, Series I
  - C
    - Connecticut Birth Control League, [n.d.] (Box 10, Folder 15)
      Geographical location: [s.l.], CT
      Subjects: Birth control--Connecticut
      Comments: Contains "Human values in our democracy," by Robins W. Barstow [ca. 1939-45].
    - Connecticut Child Study and Treatment Home, 1944-1959 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      Subjects: Mental health--Connecticut; Child abuse--Connecticut.
      Comments: Contains a fact sheet and a description of the High Meadows residential psychiatric-care facility in Hamden, CT.
    - Connecticut Civil Liberties Union, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      Geographical location: CT
      Subjects: Civil rights--Connecticut; Religion and politics--Connecticut.
      Name changes etc.: CCLU
      Comments: CCLU, an affiliate of the American Civil Liberties Union, has chapters in Fairfield, Hartford, and New Haven counties. Contains "The Connecticut school bus law" (1958), which explains CCLU's opposition to "the use of public funds for transportation [of pupils] to private schools."
    - Connecticut Committee Opposed to Legalized Lotteries, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      Subjects: Social legislation--Connecticut; Gambling--Connecticut.
      Comments: Contains four typescripts urging defeat of gambling bills under discussion in the Connecticut legislature.
    - Connecticut Committee to Make Birth Control Legal, 1935-1941 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Geographical location: Hartford, CT
      Subjects: Birth control--Connecticut.
      Comments: Contains typescripts, periodicals, pamphlets urging repeal of Connecticut's law prohibiting any form of artificial Birth control
    - Connecticut Conference on Social and Labor Legislation (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Subjects: Civil rights--Connecticut; Social legislation--Connecticut. Labor movement
      Comments: Contains 12 issues of "Legislative Facts" (1940); three pamphlets on social and labor legislative issues; proceedings of the 2nd and 3rd annual conferences (1938, 1939); two typescripts on national defense issues.
    - Connecticut Council of Churches and Religious Education, 1937-1959 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Subjects: Social legislation--Connecticut.
      Name changes etc.: Connecticut Council of Churches, Inc.
      Comments: Contains constitution, occasional bulletins on social legislation (including gambling, mental health, liquor control, civil rights, public housing, school busing for parochial school students), pamphlets.
    - Connecticut Economic Council, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Comments: Contains single issue of "Fortnightly Letter" (1946) criticizing the Office of Price Administration (OPA).
    - Connecticut Federation of Labor, 1950-19511 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Labor movement; Civil rights--Connecticut.
      Comments: Contains publicity brochure, materials related to 65th Annual Convention (1950), mimeographed sheets re. various issues, incl. Connecticut Supreme Court decision in the Norwalk Teachers' Association v. Board of Education of the City of Norwalk case involving the right of teachers to organize themselves into a labor union.
    - Connecticut Jewish Community Relations Council, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      Subjects: Jews--Connecticut
      Comments: Contains "The range of Jewish community relations," by Bernard H. Trager (1952).
    - Connecticut Peace Council, [ca. 1954] (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Subjects: China; Peace movements--Connecticut.
      Comments: Contains "No war for Chiang Kai-Shek."
    - Connecticut Prison Association, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Subjects: Alcoholism--Connecticut; Correctional institutions--Connecticut.
      Comments: Contains "The drunkenness offender in the city and county of Hartford, Connecticut," by Charles G. Chakerian (1953).
    - Connecticut State Medical Society, 1942-[1946] (Box 11, Folder 9a)
      Subjects: Medical care--Connecticut
      Comments: Contains "This is medical care in Connecticut" (1942), and "Speakers Bureau" [1946].
    - Connecticut Temperance Foundation, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      Subjects: Alcoholism--Connecticut.
      Comments: Contains typescripts on Connecticut liquor laws (1939).
    - Connecticut Temperance and Anti-Saloon League, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Comments: Contains typescripts on liquor bills in the Connecticut legislature (1937).
    - Connecticut United Nations Association, [ca. 1944] (Box 11, Folder 12)
      Subjects: International organization.
      Comments: Contains "Make your vote count against a third world war" and results of a survey of Connecticut congressional candidates regarding their support for the United Nations.
    - Connecticut, State of--Department of Health, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Subjects: Medical care--Connecticut.
      Comments: Contains "Major activities [of the Department]" (1940).
    - Connecticut, State of--Inter-Racial Commission, 1944-1947 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Subjects: Race relations--Connecticut.
      Comments: Contains "Laws against discrimination" (1945); report to the governor (1944); "A brief description of the Connecticut Fair Employment Practices Act" (1947); and single issue of "The Connecticut Inter-Racial Survey" (1945).
    - Constitutional Educational League, 1937-1945 (Box 50, Folder 1-2)
      Subjects: Labor Movement Propaganda
      Comments: contains paper and pamphlets from and about the League's reactionary, anti-union activities; includes pamphlet making disparaging reference to Dean Pope and his reply.
    - Constructive Psychology, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1)
      Geographical location: Brevard, NC
      Subjects: Cults
      Comments: contains newsletter
    - Consultation on Church Union, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      Subjects: Ecumenical movement
      Comments: Contains "Principles of church union" (1966).
    - Consumers Cooperative Movement in the U.S.A., [n.d.] (Box 11, Folder 14)
      Subjects: Cooperative societies.
      Comments: Contains organization chart; "Explanation of official chart of the...Consumers Cooperative Movement in the U.S.A."
    - Consumers Union, [1939-1945] (Box 11, Folder 17)
      Subjects: Commercial products--Testing.
      Comments: Contains advertising brochures.
    - Consumers' League of Connecticut, 1940-1945 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      Comments: Contains two pamphlets on labor laws; two issues of "Industrial News Letter" (1944-45); two solicitation letters.
    - Consumers' League of New York, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      Comments: Pamphlet re. migrant farm workers:"What's Next for New York's Joads?"
    - Continuing Committee on Muslim-Christian Cooperation, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      Geographical location: Bhamdoun, [Lebanon]
      Subjects: Ecumenical movement; Christianity--Relations--Islam. Islam--Relations--Christianity.
      Name changes etc.: Continuing Committee for Muslim-Christian Cooperation
      Comments: Contains "Statement of purpose" (1954).
    - Cooperative Commonwealth Federation, ca. 1941 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Geographical location: Ottawa, Canada
      Subjects: World War, 1939-1945; Economic policy
      Comments: Pamphlet: "A New Order Shall Arise"
    - Cooperative Consumers of New Haven (1 of 2), 1937-1961 (Box 50)
      Subjects: Cooperative societies; New Haven
      Comments: newsletters and papers about the Cooperative's activities; contains materials from a 1941 study of New England Cooperatives by the New Haven Cooperative; large collection of Co-op bulletins in Box 103
    - Cooperative Consumers of New Haven (2 of 2) (Box 103)
    - Cooperative Credit Union, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Subjects: Cooperative societies--Connecticut.
      Comments: Leaflet: "How to Save Money in Buying a Car".
    - Cooperative Health Federation of America, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Subjects: Cooperative societies; Medical care
      Name changes etc.: CHFA
      Comments: Contains "What is the Cooperative Health Federation?" [n.d.]; two issues of "CHFA Information Letter" (1953).
    - Cooperative League of the U.S.A., 1940-1954 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      Subjects: Cooperative societies
      Comments: contains papers and pamphlets about the activities of the national umbrella group of the cooperative movement
    - Coordinating Center for Democratic Opinion, [1968] (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Radicalism.
      Comments: Contains "An open letter to Senator [Eugene] McCarthy" attacking New Left politics.
    - Council Child Development Center, [n.d.] (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Subjects: Education; Child development.
      Comments: Contains "The child entering nursery school: a study of intake principles and procedures."
    - Council for Clinical Training, Inc., 1956 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      Subjects: Chaplains, Hospital.
      Comments: Contains "Quarterly announcements" of clinical pastoral training programs for hospital Chaplains
    - Council for Democracy, 1941-1946 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      Subjects: Antisemitism; Economic policy; International relations;Race relations; Labor movement
      Comments: Contains "Nazi poison" (1941); "Inflation in one easy lesson" [n.d.]; two issues of "Today" (1946); one issue of "Write Now" (1946).
    - Council for Equal Job Opportunity, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      Subjects: Race relations; Employment--Pennsylvania.
      Comments: Contains "FEPC [Fair Employment Practice Committee] helps business" [n.d.]; "Statements of witnesses...on behalf of Council for Equal Job Opportunity in support of Fair Employment Practices Ordinance" (1948).
    - Council for Inter-Church Cooperation, 1950-1951 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      Subjects: Ecumenical movement--Connecticut.
      Comments: Contains two issues of "The Inter-Church Newsletter."
    - Council for Religion in Independent Schools, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      Subjects: Christian Education; Freedom of religion
      Comments: Contains "Religion in education" (1953).
    - Council for Social Action (see Congregational Christian Churches--Council for Social Action and United Church of Christ--Council for Social Action)
    - Council of Women for Home Missions, 1940, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 13)
      Subjects: Migrant labor; Rural conditions
      Name changes etc.: See also: Home Missions Council
      Comments: Materials re. migrant farm workers.
    - Council on Christian Social Progress (see Northern Baptist Convention--Council on Christian Social Progress)
    - Council on Education in Race Relations, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      Subjects: Communism; Race relations; Subversive activities.
      Comments: Contains letter in re Dr. Rufus Clark, in which Clark was accused of having a "Communist-front record" (1952), four supporting documents.
    - Council on Religion and International Affairs, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      Subjects: Religion and international affairs; Peace movements
      Comments: contains pamphlets issued by the Council which believes that "the ethical principles of the major religions are relevant to the world's political, economic and social problems", and papers from a conference on revolution and international organization.
    - Current, 1964 (Box 106, Folder 2)
      Subjects: John Fitzgerald Kennedy; United States--politics and government
      Comments: contains issue of Current magazine dealing with the significance of the life and death of John F. Kennedy
  - D
    - Danforth Foundation, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      Comments: Contains two issues of "Danforth News and Notes" (1966-67) with articles on "Negro" colleges, excellence in teaching, student conformity, campus ministry.
    - Detroit Industrial Mission, 1961 (Box 97, Folder 3)
      Geographical location: Detroit, IL
      Subjects: Labor movement; Missions
      Comments: contains newsletter of mission activities in industrial plants
    - Disciples of Christ - Division of Social Education, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      Geographical location: Indianapolis, IN
      Subjects: World War, 1939-1945; Peace movements
      Name changes etc.: United Christian Missionary Society
      Comments: Peace Resolutions
    - Disciples of Christ--Committee on Military and Veterans Service, 1952-1953 (Box 12, Folder 19)
      Subjects: Armed Forces; Chaplains
      Comments: Contains two issues of "The Disciple Chaplain" (1952-53).
    - Dixwell Community House, [1944] (Box 12, Folder 20)
      Subjects: Community organization; New Haven.
      Comments: Contains membership drive pamphlet describing organization's activities.
    - Dixwell Group, 1943-1946 (Box 97, Folder 2)
      Subjects: Community organization; New Haven; Race relations
      Comments: contains newsletters and program reports issued by the group: an organization of Yale students and New Haven residents to address issues within New Haven
  - E
    - E.I. du Pont de Nemours and Company, 1952-1957 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Geographical location: [DE]
      Subjects: Education; Citizenship. Technology.
      Comments: Contains "Technology--Hope or hobgoblin?" by Henry B. du Pont (1952); "Individual responsibility," by Crawford H. Greenewalt (1954); "Technology and the liberal arts," by Henry B. du Pont (1955); and "New paths for new pioneers," by Henry B. du Pont (1957).
    - East Harlem Protestant Parish, 1950-1969 (Box 13, Folder 1-1c)
      Comments: Monthly reports to Administrative Board 1950-1958; two issues of newsletter (1969).
    - East and West Association, 1947-1948 (Box 12, Folder 24)
      Subjects: Japan.
      Comments: Contains two solicitation letters; one pamphlet publicizing a speaking tour by the Rev. Toru Matsumoto.
    - Eastern Cooperative League, 1938-[1943] (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Comments: Contains "The important fact about a cooperative--" [1943], and "Cooperation--Our new frontier" (1938).
    - Eastern Cooperatives, Inc., 1941-1950 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      Geographical location: Brooklyn, NY; New York, NY; Palisades Park, NJ
      Comments: Contains eight issues of "The Cooperator" (most from 1950).
    - Economic Cooperation Administration, 1950, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 4)
      Subjects: International relief; Economic policy
      Comments: Several pamphlets re. Marshall Plan and European recovery after World War II.
    - Ecumenical Council of Churches in Czechoslovakia, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Subjects: Ecumenical movement; Czechoslovakia
      Comments: Newsletters
    - Ecumenical Institute, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Subjects: Race relations; Ecumenical movemen
      Comments: Contains two issues of "Image" (1963, 1967).
    - Educators' Committee on the Status of Jerusalem, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Subjects: Jews; Israel-Arab conflicts.
      Comments: Contains press release "One thousand American educators oppose political internationalization of Jerusalem" [1950]; letter to President Harry S Truman (1950).
    - Electronic Corporation of America, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Subjects: Economic policy; World War, 1939-1945
      Comments: Contains "A plan for...America at peace" (1944).
    - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1952-1955 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Civil rights; Communism; Subversive activities.
      Comments: Contains nine issues of "Rights" (1953-55); two copies of "Risk for risk," by Learned Hand (1952); "Mind of your own: Harvey O'Connor's stand" (1953).
    - Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars, 1934-1942 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Subjects: Refugees; Academic freedom; World War, 1939-1945
      Name changes etc.: Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced German Scholars
      Comments: Annual reports.
    - Emergency Committee to Save the Jewish People of Europe, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Subjects: Jews; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Palestine; World War, 1939-1945; Refugees
      Comments: Contains single issue of "The Answer Magazine" (1944).
    - Episcopal Church Center--Division of Christian Citizenship--Department of Christian Social Relations, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      Comments: Contains single issue of "Church and race" (1963) that reported on the Aug. 28, 1963, civil-rights march on Washington, DC.
    - Episcopal League for Social Action, [1951] (Box 14, Folder 9)
      Comments: Contains "Christ's feast or the devil's?", by Joseph F. Fletcher [1951].
    - Episcopal Pacifist Fellowship, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      Subjects: World War, 1939-1945; Chaplains; Religion and politics
      Comments: Contains "The chaplain and the church" (1943), which urges churches to provide military chaplains at their own, rather than government, expense to avoid church/state entanglements.
    - Episcopal Society for Cultural and Racial Unity, 1960-1965 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      Subjects: Civil rights; Ecumenical movement; Race relations
      Comments: Contains statement by "religious leaders and heads of organizations working for improved human relations," sent to Sen. John F. Kennedy and Vice President Richard M. Nixon, urging each "to provide leadership in the struggle against prejudice and discrimination" if elected President of the United States (1960); "Address to the annual meeting...by Charles F. Wittenstein on the civil rights and ecumenical movements (1965).
    - Eugenics Board of North Carolina, [1954-1960] (Box 14, Folder 12)
      Geographical location: Raleigh, NC
      Subjects: Medical ethics; Eugenics--North Carolina
      Comments: Contains two pamphlets on North Carolina's sterilization program.
    - Eugenics Society of Northern California, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 4)
      Geographical location: Sacramento, CA
      Subjects: Birth control; Eugenics
      Comments: contains pamphlets issued by the society about eugenics and world population problems
    - European Christian Mission, 1947-1949 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      Geographical location: Brooklyn, NY; Toronto, ON (Canada)
      Subjects: Jews; Christianity--Relations--Judaism; Palestine; International relief.
      Comments: Contains five issues of "The Jew and Palestine News" (1947-48); two issues of "Europe's Millions" (1947, 1949); "Help Europe's Starving, Destitute Preachers and Believers" [n.d.]; and solicitation letter [ca. 1948]
    - European Youth Committee of the International Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1962 (Box 104, Folder 2)
      Subjects: International relations; Youth
      Comments: contains 7 issues of the committee's newsletter VIA PACIS, May-December 1962
    - Euthanasia Society of America, 1939-1951 (Box 14, Folder 14)
      Subjects: Medical ethics; Euthanasia.
      Comments: Contains miscellaneous pamphlets, posters, solicitation letters, draft proposals, radio script, bibliography, historical notes, and press clippings relating to voluntary euthanasia.
    - Evangelical United Brethren Church--Commission on Christian Social Action, [ca. 1947] (Box 14, Folder 17)
      Geographical location: Dayton, OH; Harrisburg, PA
      Comments: Contains "The church and the alcohol problem" [ca. 1947].
    - Evangelical and Reformed Church--Board of Christian Education and Publication, [1946] (Box 14, Folder 15)
      Subjects: Race relations; Witchcraft.
      Comments: Contains "Witchcraft and race prejudice."
    - Evangelical and Reformed Church--Commission on Christian Social Action, 1941-1949 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      Subjects: Economic policy; Race relations; Refugees
      Comments: Contains "The Christian and the profit-motive" (1941); press release in re the Displaced Persons Act (1949); "Report of the Secretary for Race Relations to Commission on Christian Social Action...." (1949).
  - F
    - Fair Play for Cuba Committee, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 18)
      Subjects: International relations; Cuba.
      Comments: Leaflets protesting attack on Cuba.
    - Faith for Today, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      Geographical location: Forest Hills, NY
      Comments: Contains typescript of telecast on how divorce affects children.
    - Farmers Federation--Religious Department, [n.d.] (Box 14, Folder 20)
      Geographical location: Ashville, NC
      Subjects: Rural conditions; Agriculture
      Comments: The Lord's Acre Plan is "the raising of a dedicated crop, or stock, selling the produce and giving the cash proceeds to the church." Contains "The country church needs the Lord's Acre Plan" [n.d.].
    - Federal Communications Commission, 1961-1962 (Box 14, Folder 21)
      Subjects: Broadcasting
      Name changes etc.: FCC
      Comments: Contains speeches by James T. Aubrey, Jr., Richard S. Salant, and Frank Stanton before the Federal Communications Commission (1962); speech by Leroy Collins to members of the Radio and Television Executives Society of New York (1961).
    - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America, 1942-1948 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      Subjects: Ecumenical movement; International relations; Race relations; Refugees
      Name changes etc.: later known as the National Council of Churches of Christ in America
      Comments: contains papers and pamphlets about the ecumenical body and its activities; included are papers from the 1944 biennial meeting
    - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America - Information Service, 1939-1946 (Box 53, Folder 2a)
      Subjects: Religion and culture; World War, 1939-1945
      Comments: contains issues of the Information Service newsletter issued during and commenting on the war; for complete collection see YDS periodicals call no. ZP IN34
    - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America-- Department of Pastoral Services, 1948 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      Subjects: Correctional institutions; Medical care; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains a paper about Protestant institutional ministries
    - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America--Commission for a Just and Durable Peace, 1943-1950 (Box 51, Folder 3,4)
      Subjects: Ecumenical movement; International relations; World War, 1939-1945
      Comments: contains papers and pamphlets about the commission's activities in international relations
    - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America--Commission on the Church and Minority Peoples, 1944, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 2)
      Comments: contains papers about the church and race relations and a 1944 nationwide survey of clergy
    - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America--Department of International Justice and Goodwill, 1942-1954 (Box 52, Folder 3)
      Subjects: International Relations; Nuclear disarmament; Religion and culture; Religion and international affairs
      Comments: contains papers and pamphlets about the Council's position on and activities in international relations
    - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America--Department of Race Relations, 1937-1949 (Box 52, Folder 5-5a)
      Subjects: Church and social problems; Race relations; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains papers and pamphlets on race relations in the Church and in society; including several issues of the Interracial News Service (for complete collection see YDS periodical, call no. ZP IN99)
    - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America--Department of the Church and Economic life, 1947-1950 (Box 52, Folder 1-1b)
      Subjects: Economic policy; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains papers and pamphlets about the Church's relationship to aspects of American economic life
    - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America--Department of the Church and Social Services, 1919-1948 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      Subjects: Church and social problems; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains papers and pamphlets on the Church's relationship to the social and economic order; including several drafts and published copies of the Council's annual Labor Day message
    - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America--Executive Council, 1946-1950 (Box 53, Folder 1)